<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="https://periodicos.ufsc.br/lib/pkp/xml/oai2.xsl" ?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/
		http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
	<responseDate>2015-05-17T20:48:30Z</responseDate>
	<request verb="GetRecord" metadataPrefix="oai_dc" identifier="oai:periodicos.ufsc.br:article/293">https://periodicos.ufsc.br/index.php/eb/oai</request>
	<GetRecord>
		<record>
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:periodicos.ufsc.br:article/293</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-01-26T15:38:16Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>eb:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc
	xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/
	http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Mapping the use of competitive intelligence (CI) and knowledge management (KM) at the health secto</dc:title>
	<dc:title xml:lang="pt-BR">Mapeamento de inteligência competitiva (IC) e de gestão do conhecimento (GC) no setor saúde 10.5007/1518-2924.2004v9nesp1p78</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Canongia, Claudia; Inmetro - Rio de Janeiro - RJ</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Pereira, Maria de Nazaré F; IBICT - Brasília - DF</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Mendes, Cristina d´Urso de Souza; UFRJ - Rio de Janeiro - RJ</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Antunes, Adelaide Maria de Souza; UFRJ - Rio de Janeiro - RJ</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="pt-BR">Ciência da Informação; Information Science; Biblioteconomia; Library Science</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="pt-BR">Inteligência competitiva; Gestão do conhecimento; Gestão da inovação; Setor Saúde; ISI Web of Science; Competitive intelligence; Knowledge management; Innovation management; Health sector</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="pt-BR">I. Information treatement for information services</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Knowledge and innovation are key factors of competitiviness and development in the global society. New models for management like Competitive Intelligence (CI) and Knowledge Management (KM) are being considered in the literature as methodologies which enable growth and innovation. This paper presents the results of the application of the concepts and techniques of CI and KM in the Health sector, using articles indexed on the ISI Web of Science databases for the years 1990/2003. Knowledge maps are presented using text mining techniques for the analysis of the evolution of publications, identification of institutions, partnerships and content analysis for presentation of the main approaches being used in the selected articles.</dc:description>
	<dc:description xml:lang="pt-BR">Conhecimento e inovação são variáveis-chave de competitividade e de desenvolvimento na sociedade global. Novos modelos de gestão como a inteligência competitiva (IC) e a gestão do conhecimento (GC) vêm sendo discutidos na literatura como metodologias catalisadoras de crescimento e inovação. Neste trabalho são apresentados resultados da aplicação de conceitos e técnicas de IC e GC em estudos do setor Saúde utilizando-se artigos indexados em três bases do ISI Web of Science, no período 1990/2003. São apresentados mapas de conhecimento decorrentes de text mining, para análise da evolução de publicação, identificação de instituições, parcerias e análises de conteúdo para verificação dos principais enfoques adotados.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="pt-BR">Departamento de Ciência da Informação – UFSC</dc:publisher>
	<dc:contributor xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:contributor>
	<dc:date>2004-01-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://periodicos.ufsc.br/index.php/eb/article/view/1518-2924.2004v9nesp1p78</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.5007/1518-2924.2004v9nesp1p78</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Encontros Bibli: revista eletrônica de biblioteconomia e ciência da informação; Especial - primeiro semestre de 2004: Inteligência competitiva; 78-95</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="pt-BR">Encontros Bibli: revista eletrônica de biblioteconomia e ciência da informação; Especial - primeiro semestre de 2004: Inteligência competitiva; 78-95</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1518-2924</dc:source>
	<dc:language>por</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://periodicos.ufsc.br/index.php/eb/article/view/1518-2924.2004v9nesp1p78/5283</dc:relation>
	<dc:coverage xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
	</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
