<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="https://periodicos.ufsc.br/lib/pkp/xml/oai2.xsl" ?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/
		http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
	<responseDate>2015-05-17T20:49:37Z</responseDate>
	<request verb="GetRecord" metadataPrefix="oai_dc" identifier="oai:periodicos.ufsc.br:article/197">https://periodicos.ufsc.br/index.php/eb/oai</request>
	<GetRecord>
		<record>
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:periodicos.ufsc.br:article/197</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-01-26T15:37:39Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>eb:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc
	xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/
	http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Documentary management of the sport audio-visual information in the generalist televisions</dc:title>
	<dc:title xml:lang="pt-BR">Gestión documental de la información audiovisual deportiva en las televisiones generalistas 10.5007/1518-2924.2005v10n20p1</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Serrano, Jorge Caldera; Universidad de Extremadura</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Alonso, Felipe; Universidad de Extremadura</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="pt-BR">Ciência da Informação; Information Science; Biblioteconomia; Library Science</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="pt-BR">Documentación audiovisual;  Información deportiva;  Televisión; Audio-visual documentation; Sport information; Television; Sport</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="pt-BR">HH. Audio-visual, Multimedia.</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">The management of the sport audio-visual documentation of the Information Systems of the state, zonal and local chains is analyzed within the framework. For it it is made
makes a route by the documentary chain that makes the sport audio-visual information with the purpose of being analyzing each one of the parameters, showing therefore a
series of recommendations and norms for the preparation of the sport audio-visual registry. Evidently the audio-visual sport documentation difference in excess of the
analysis of other televising documentary types reason why is not carried out a deepening and extension of its management and diffusion, showing the informational
flow within the System.</dc:description>
	<dc:description xml:lang="pt-BR">Se analiza la gestión de la información audiovisual deportiva en el marco de los Sistemas de Información Documental de las cadenas estatales, zonales y locales. Para ello se realiza un realiza un recorrido por la cadena documental que realiza la información audiovisual deportiva con el fin de ir analizando cada uno de los parámetros, mostrando así una serie de recomendaciones y normativas para la confección del registro audiovisual deportivo. Evidentemente la documentación deportiva audiovisual no se diferencia en exceso del análisis de otros tipos documentales televisivos por lo que se lleva a cabo una profundización y ampliación de su gestión y difusión, mostrando el flujo informacional dentro del Sistema.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="pt-BR">Departamento de Ciência da Informação – UFSC</dc:publisher>
	<dc:contributor xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:contributor>
	<dc:date>2007-11-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://periodicos.ufsc.br/index.php/eb/article/view/1518-2924.2005v10n20p1</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.5007/1518-2924.2005v10n20p1</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Encontros Bibli: revista eletrônica de biblioteconomia e ciência da informação; v. 10, n. 20 (2005); 1-20</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="pt-BR">Encontros Bibli: revista eletrônica de biblioteconomia e ciência da informação; v. 10, n. 20 (2005); 1-20</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1518-2924</dc:source>
	<dc:language>por</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://periodicos.ufsc.br/index.php/eb/article/view/1518-2924.2005v10n20p1/301</dc:relation>
	<dc:coverage xml:lang="pt-BR">Espanha</dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
	</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
