<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="https://periodicos.ufsc.br/lib/pkp/xml/oai2.xsl" ?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/
		http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
	<responseDate>2015-05-17T20:48:26Z</responseDate>
	<request verb="GetRecord" metadataPrefix="oai_dc" identifier="oai:periodicos.ufsc.br:article/34">https://periodicos.ufsc.br/index.php/eb/oai</request>
	<GetRecord>
		<record>
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:periodicos.ufsc.br:article/34</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-01-26T15:39:34Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>eb:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc
	xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/
	http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="pt-BR">O ensino da área de controle sobre a perspectiva da competência: experiência no curso de Biblioteconomia da UFSC 10.5007/1518-2924.1999v4n8p16</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Bohn, Maria Del Carmen; UFSC - Florianópolis - SC</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="pt-BR">Desenvolvimento de Competências; Ciência da Informação; Formação do Profissional; Ciência da Informação; Ensino de Controle Bibliográfico;  Development of Competence; Library Science; Education of professionals; Library Science; Teaching; Librar</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="pt-BR">GG. Curricula aspects. GH. Education.</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">This article, first, presents some tendencies on current education and relates the social demands of globalisation and technological advances to the education of professionals in Library and Information Science. Second, it introduces the concepts of “knowledge” and “competence”, showing how they can be approached in some of the disciplines of Library and Information Science, and how they cam be integrated with the concepts of what literature has been calling recently as ‘knowing what” in opposition to “knowing how”. The article concludes proposing that library programs, because of the professionals activities information science professionals will be involved in, should contemplate the development of both knowledges, “knowing what”- emphasising the development of academic skills, and “knowing how”- the ability to interpret knowledges for the solution of problems.</dc:description>
	<dc:description xml:lang="pt-BR">O artigo apresenta algumas tendências da educação atual relacionando as demandas da globalização e dos avanços tecnológicos com a formação do profissional na Ciência da Informação. Introduz-se os conceitos de ‘conhecimento’ e de ‘competência’, mostrando como podem ser abordados em algumas das disciplinas do Currículo de Biblioteconomia, integrando aquilo que a literatura tem recentemente chamado de saber em oposição ao saber fazer. Conclui-se que a ação pedagógica, devido ao trabalho profissional em que os profissionais de biblioteconomia se envolvem, deve contemplar o desenvolvimento de ambos os saberes tanto nos conteúdos dos programas como nas interações dos alunos.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="pt-BR">Departamento de Ciência da Informação – UFSC</dc:publisher>
	<dc:contributor xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:contributor>
	<dc:date>1999-01-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="pt-BR">Reflexão</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://periodicos.ufsc.br/index.php/eb/article/view/1518-2924.1999v4n8p16</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.5007/1518-2924.1999v4n8p16</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Encontros Bibli: revista eletrônica de biblioteconomia e ciência da informação; v. 4, n. 8 (1999); 16-19</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="pt-BR">Encontros Bibli: revista eletrônica de biblioteconomia e ciência da informação; v. 4, n. 8 (1999); 16-19</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1518-2924</dc:source>
	<dc:language>por</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://periodicos.ufsc.br/index.php/eb/article/view/1518-2924.1999v4n8p16/5048</dc:relation>
	<dc:coverage xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
	</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
