<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="https://agora.emnuvens.com.br/lib/pkp/xml/oai2.xsl" ?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/
		http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
	<responseDate>2015-09-06T12:26:43Z</responseDate>
	<request verb="GetRecord" metadataPrefix="oai_dc" identifier="oai:agora.periodicos.emnuvens.com.br:article/540">https://agora.emnuvens.com.br/ra/oai</request>
	<GetRecord>
		<record>
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:agora.periodicos.emnuvens.com.br:article/540</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-03-25T20:30:12Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>ra:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc
	xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/
	http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Insert professional and contributions in theory of archivist management judicial power documentary</dc:title>
	<dc:title xml:lang="pt-BR">Inserção profissional e contribuições teóricas do arquivista na gestão documental do poder judiciário</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Marques, Otacílio Guedes; Universidade de Brasília</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Manini, Miriam Paula; Faculdade de Ciência da Informação da Universidade de Brasília</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Information Science; Archival; Library</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Archivist; Archival; Professional insertion; Judiciary</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Professional insertion</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="pt-BR">Ciência da Informação; Biblioteconomia; Arquivologia</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="pt-BR">Arquivista; Arquivologia; Inserção Profissional; Poder Judiciário</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="pt-BR">Arquivologia</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">This article presents survey regarding the employability and theoretical contributions to the document management Archivists in the judiciary. We tried to initially contextualize the history of the discipline in Brazil, with the main moments of its consolidation, through the actions of the National Archives, association, until the creation of the top courses Bachelor of archival. The aim is to identify, classify and analyze the emergence and consolidation of Archivology in Brazil, the academic and professional environments, through its insertion to its consolidation in the judiciary, developing through the survey and analysis: a) of the notices public procurement of the organs of the Brazilian courts, carried out between the years 1999-2014, for the provision of the Judicial Analyst positions - Specialty archivist; b) and events (conferences, seminars, forums, etc.) with archival issues dealing with the judiciary archives. In this sense, we intend to support as professionals, work and archival practice in the Judiciary Power has been treated and placed in these institutions.</dc:description>
	<dc:description xml:lang="pt-BR">O presente artigo apresenta levantamento referente à inserção profissional e às contribuições teóricas dos arquivistas à gestão documental no Poder Judiciário. Buscou-se, inicialmente, contextualizar a trajetória da disciplina no Brasil, apresentando os principais momentos da sua consolidação, por meio das ações do Arquivo Nacional, do associativismo, até a criação dos cursos superiores de bacharelado em Arquivologia. Busca-se identificar, sistematizar e analisar o surgimento e a consolidação da Arquivologia no Brasil, nos ambientes acadêmico e profissional, passando por sua inserção até sua consolidação no Poder Judiciário, desenvolvendo-se por meio do levantamento e análise: a) dos editais dos concursos públicos dos órgãos do Poder Judiciário brasileiro, realizados entre os anos de 1999 a 2014, para o provimento do cargo de Analista Judiciário – Especialidade arquivista; b) e dos eventos com temáticas arquivísticas (Congressos, Seminários, Fóruns etc.) tratando dos arquivos do Poder Judiciário. Nesse sentido, pretende-se fundamentar como os profissionais, o trabalho e a prática arquivística nos órgãos do Poder Judiciário vêm sendo tratados e inseridos nessas instituições.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="pt-BR">ÁGORA ISSN 0103-3557</dc:publisher>
	<dc:contributor xml:lang="en-US"></dc:contributor>
	<dc:contributor xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:contributor>
	<dc:date>2015-03-23</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en-US"></dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://agora.emnuvens.com.br/ra/article/view/540</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="pt-BR">ÁGORA ISSN 0103-3557; v. 25, n. 50 (2015); 61-84</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0103-3557</dc:source>
	<dc:language>por</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://agora.emnuvens.com.br/ra/article/view/540/pdf_86</dc:relation>
	<dc:coverage xml:lang="en-US">Brazil</dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage xml:lang="en-US"></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage xml:lang="en-US"></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage xml:lang="pt-BR">Brasilia; Brasil</dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage xml:lang="pt-BR">Modernismo</dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:coverage>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="pt-BR">Direitos autorais 2015 ÁGORA, ISSN 0103-3557, Florianópolis</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
	</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
