<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://www.revistas.usp.br/lib/pkp/xml/oai2.xsl" ?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/
		http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
	<responseDate>2015-05-17T21:30:34Z</responseDate>
	<request verb="GetRecord" metadataPrefix="oai_dc" identifier="oai:www.revistas.usp.br:article/42340">http://www.revistas.usp.br/incid/oai</request>
	<GetRecord>
		<record>
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:www.revistas.usp.br:article/42340</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-04-14T11:20:28Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>incid:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc
	xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/
	http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">The knowledge organization systems in the current perspectives of the international guides for the construction</dc:title>
	<dc:title xml:lang="pt-BR">Os sistemas de organização do conhecimento nas perspectivas atuais das normas internacionais de construção</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Boccato, Vera Regina Casari; Universidade Federal de São Carlos, Centro de Educação e Ciências Humanas, Departamento de Ciências da Informação.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Organização do conhecimento; Represnetação temática da informação; linguagens documentárias</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">International Standards; Construction; Knowledge organization systems; Information Retrieval System; Web environment</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="pt-BR">Organização do conhecimento; Represnetação temática da informação; linguagens documentárias</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="pt-BR">Normas internacionais, Construção, Sistemas de organização do conhecimento; Sistema de informação, Ambiente web</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="pt-BR">Realizou-ser  um estudo dos sistemas de organização do conhecimento pelas perspectivas das normas internacionais de construção, verificando-se as ampliações e as modificações mais significativas ocorridas entre as elas, a partir dos vocabulários controlados abordados. O objetivo é apresentar as concepções, as funções e características de cada um deles, delimitando e, ao mesmo tempo, generalizando suas  aplicações nos mais diversos contextos de uso, pelas perspectivas evolutivas das normas internacionais para a Organização e Recuperação da Informação em Ciência da Informação.O universo de pesquisa foi  as normas internacionais ANSI/NISO Z39.19-2005, BS 8723 e ISO  25964, com destaque para as taxonomias, tesauros, ontologias e folksonomias como vocabulários controlados analisados. Os resultados desse estudo apontaram, principalmente, sobre a necessidade contínua de atualização das normas internacionais, frente as inovações tecnológicas e  informacionais ocorridas na Organização e Recuperação do Conhecimento  em Ciência da Informação e no contexto do usuário especializado ou não.</dc:description>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">We conducted a study of the knowledge organization systems for the perspectives of international standards for the construction, verifying the extensions and the most significant changes occurred between them from the controlled vocabulary addressed. The aim is to present the concepts, functions and characteristics of each, and delimiting, at the same time, generalizing their applications in various contexts of use, for the perspectives of international standards for the Information Organization and Retrieval in Information Science. The research base was the international standards ANSI/NISO Z39.19-2005, BS 8723 and ISO 25964, especially the classification schemes, subject headings schemes, taxonomies, thesauri and ontologies, as well as synonyn rings, business classification schemes for records management and semantic networks as controlled vocabularies analyzed. The results of this study showed, mainly, on the continuing need to update international standards, for the technological innovations and informational occurred in Knowledge Organization and Retrieval in Information Science and in the specialized or not users’ context.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="pt-BR">Universidade de São Paulo. Faculdade de Filosofia, Ciências e Letras de Ribeirão Preto</dc:publisher>
	<dc:contributor xml:lang="en-US"></dc:contributor>
	<dc:contributor xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:contributor>
	<dc:date>2011-06-02</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en-US"></dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>http://www.revistas.usp.br/incid/article/view/42340</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.11606/issn.2178-2075.v2i1p165-192</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="pt-BR">InCID: Revista de Ciência da Informação e Documentação; v. 2, n. 1 (2011); 165-192</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2178-2075</dc:source>
	<dc:language>por</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>http://www.revistas.usp.br/incid/article/view/42340/46011</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
	</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
