<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://www.revistas.usp.br/lib/pkp/xml/oai2.xsl" ?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/
		http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
	<responseDate>2015-05-17T21:32:44Z</responseDate>
	<request verb="GetRecord" metadataPrefix="oai_dc" identifier="oai:www.revistas.usp.br:article/42369">http://www.revistas.usp.br/incid/oai</request>
	<GetRecord>
		<record>
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:www.revistas.usp.br:article/42369</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-04-14T11:19:11Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>incid:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc
	xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/
	http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="pt-BR">Informação e documento: expressão material do patrimônio</dc:title>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Information and document: material expression of  heritage</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Grigoleto, Maira Cristina</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="pt-BR">Informação; Documento; Patrimônio</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Information, Document, Heritage</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="pt-BR"> A constituição do patrimônio como prática institucional tem chamado a atenção de estudiosos desde o século XVIII e ainda é um campo bastante polêmico, pois muitas questões em torno das ações preservacionistas foram discutidas levando em conta mais os critérios normativos destas práticas do que a compreensão dos mecanismos metodológicos e burocráticos necessários para sua existência. Assim, propomos nesse trabalho enfatizar a importância do universo da produção documental no âmbito institucional da patrimonialização objetivando mostrar o valor que é atribuído à documentação que garante o tombamento como uma expressão material.</dc:description>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">The constitution of heritage as an institutional practice has interested researchers since the eighteenth century and it is still a very controversial field. Many issues concerning preservationist actions were discussed in which the normative criteria of these practices were more extensively considered than the understanding of the methodological and bureaucratic mechanisms necessary for their existence. Therefore, we propose in this study to stress the importance of the documental production universe in the institutional patrimonialization aiming to show the value that is assigned to the documentation that ensures the listing of buildings as a material expression.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="pt-BR">Universidade de São Paulo. Faculdade de Filosofia, Ciências e Letras de Ribeirão Preto</dc:publisher>
	<dc:contributor xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:contributor>
	<dc:date>2012-06-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en-US"></dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>http://www.revistas.usp.br/incid/article/view/42369</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.11606/issn.2178-2075.v3i1p57-69</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="pt-BR">InCID: Revista de Ciência da Informação e Documentação; v. 3, n. 1 (2012); 57-69</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2178-2075</dc:source>
	<dc:language>por</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>http://www.revistas.usp.br/incid/article/view/42369/46040</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
	</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
