<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="https://periodicos.ufsc.br/lib/pkp/xml/oai2.xsl" ?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/
		http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
	<responseDate>2015-05-17T20:50:20Z</responseDate>
	<request verb="GetRecord" metadataPrefix="oai_dc" identifier="oai:periodicos.ufsc.br:article/15">https://periodicos.ufsc.br/index.php/eb/oai</request>
	<GetRecord>
		<record>
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:periodicos.ufsc.br:article/15</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-01-26T15:39:18Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>eb:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc
	xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/
	http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">The professional system brazilian librarian: its capacity to answer to the changes of the environment economic and politician in the beginning of century XXI; a boarding under the perspective of the communicative action</dc:title>
	<dc:title xml:lang="pt-BR">O sistema profissional bibliotecário brasileiro: sua capacidade de responder às mudanças do ambiente político e econômico no início do século XXI; uma abordagem sob a perspectiva da ação comunicativa 10.5007/1518-2924.2000v5n10p11</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Souza, Francisco das Chagas de; UFSC - Florianópolis, SC</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="pt-BR">Ciência da Informação; Information Science; Biblioteconomia; Library Science</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="pt-BR">Bibliotecário; Sociedade; Brasil; Ensino de Biblioteconomia; Sistema profissional; Ação comunicativa; Brazilian librarian; Brazilian society; Brazilian librarian education; Librarianship and professional systems;  Librarianship and communicative action</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="pt-BR">A. Theoretical and general aspects of libraries and information</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">This article is a theoretical discussion, based on sociological principles which constitute the structural composition of the profession of librarian, from a systemic  perspective of world organisation, according to  Habermas’ theory of communicative action and the professional typology proposed by  Freidson in his Sociology of Professions. Focusing on the structural characterisation of the daily tasks performed by the Brazilian Librarian, the article concludes that the capacity of librarians to respond to the political and economic changes of the beginning of the XXIst century depends on a clear and transparent description of the responsibilities of the information professional and how the Brazilian Library Professional System is structured. If the theoretical principles discussed are used for the educational purposes of the librarians and for their strategic national action, these same principles may prepare the librarian to respond to the new political and economic environment of the new century.</dc:description>
	<dc:description xml:lang="pt-BR">Trata-se de artigo que resulta de pesquisa teórica, de caráter sociológico, que constrói uma caracterização da composição estrutural da profissão bibliotecária a partir da perspectiva sistêmica  e da concepção de mundo vivido originária da Teoria da Ação Comunicativa de Habermas e da tipologia profissional oriunda da Sociologia das Profissões de Freidson. Adotando esta caracterização estrutural para analisar o cotidiano vivido pela categoria bibliotecária brasileira, conclui que a capacidade da categoria bibliotecária de responder às mudanças do ambiente político e econômico no início do século XXI depende de que seja tornado  transparente e objetivo qual é e como está estruturado o Sistema Profissional Bibliotecário brasileiro. A sua explicitação e o seu uso como marco teórico para a formação de profissionais bibliotecários e para a orientação das ações bibliotecárias nacionais poderá credenciar a categoria bibliotecária para de forma eficaz e consciente responder às mudanças do ambiente político e econômico no início do século XXI.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="pt-BR">Departamento de Ciência da Informação – UFSC</dc:publisher>
	<dc:contributor xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:contributor>
	<dc:date>2000-01-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://periodicos.ufsc.br/index.php/eb/article/view/1518-2924.2000v5n10p11</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.5007/1518-2924.2000v5n10p11</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Encontros Bibli: revista eletrônica de biblioteconomia e ciência da informação; v. 5, n. 10 (2000); 11-25</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="pt-BR">Encontros Bibli: revista eletrônica de biblioteconomia e ciência da informação; v. 5, n. 10 (2000); 11-25</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1518-2924</dc:source>
	<dc:language>por</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://periodicos.ufsc.br/index.php/eb/article/view/1518-2924.2000v5n10p11/5094</dc:relation>
	<dc:coverage xml:lang="pt-BR">Brasil</dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
	</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
