<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://www.revistas.usp.br/lib/pkp/xml/oai2.xsl" ?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/
		http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
	<responseDate>2015-05-17T21:31:59Z</responseDate>
	<request verb="GetRecord" metadataPrefix="oai_dc" identifier="oai:www.revistas.usp.br:article/42359">http://www.revistas.usp.br/incid/oai</request>
	<GetRecord>
		<record>
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:www.revistas.usp.br:article/42359</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-04-14T11:20:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>incid:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc
	xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/
	http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Access to eletronic publications and its impact on libraries</dc:title>
	<dc:title xml:lang="pt-BR">Acesso às publicações eletrônicas e seu impacto na biblioteca</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Coutinho, Eliana; Fundação Oswaldo Cruz</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Machado, Rejane; Fundação Oswaldo Cruz</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Ciência da Informação</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Electronic journal; Journal subscription; Online access; Digital preservation of informational repository</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="pt-BR">Ciência da Informação</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="pt-BR">Periódico eletrônico, Assinatura de periódico, Acesso online, Preservação digital de repositório informacional</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">This work aims to characterize the coexistence of two formats (print and electronic) at the same area of current scientific journals in the FIOCRUZ Library of Biomedical Sciences, analyzing the use of these journals over the period 2009 to 2010. Besides knowing issues that underlies the acquisition process and the formats of the library’s journals, we attempted to identify editors’ policies concerning to the material contents, the allowed access period to online collections and the right of access and digital preservation. In conclusion we present some considerations regarding to the maintenance of libraries’ collections considering the growing number of electronic journals.</dc:description>
	<dc:description xml:lang="pt-BR">Este trabalho tem como premissa identificar a coexistência no mesmo domínio dos dois formatos - eletrônico e impresso - de periódicos científicos correntes da Biblioteca de Ciências Biomédicas da FIOCRUZ, a partir das constatações resultantes da análise de uso desses periódicos no período de 2009 e 2010. Além de conhecer as questões que perpassam pela aquisição e formatos dos periódicos da Biblioteca, procurou-se identificar as políticas dos editores em relação ao conteúdo do material, ao período permitido de acesso às coleções eletrônicas e ao direito de acesso e preservação digital. Como conclusão, apresentam-se pontos a serem analisados em relação à manutenção das coleções das bibliotecas tendo em vista o crescente aumento dos periódicos eletrônicos. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="pt-BR">Universidade de São Paulo. Faculdade de Filosofia, Ciências e Letras de Ribeirão Preto</dc:publisher>
	<dc:contributor xml:lang="en-US"></dc:contributor>
	<dc:contributor xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:contributor>
	<dc:date>2011-12-09</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en-US"></dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/save-as</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>http://www.revistas.usp.br/incid/article/view/42359</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.11606/issn.2178-2075.v2i2p178-188</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="pt-BR">InCID: Revista de Ciência da Informação e Documentação; v. 2, n. 2 (2011); 178-188</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2178-2075</dc:source>
	<dc:language>por</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>http://www.revistas.usp.br/incid/article/view/42359/46030</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
	</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
