<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://www.revistas.usp.br/lib/pkp/xml/oai2.xsl" ?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/
		http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
	<responseDate>2015-05-17T21:30:26Z</responseDate>
	<request verb="GetRecord" metadataPrefix="oai_dc" identifier="oai:www.revistas.usp.br:article/42338">http://www.revistas.usp.br/incid/oai</request>
	<GetRecord>
		<record>
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:www.revistas.usp.br:article/42338</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-04-14T11:20:27Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>incid:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc
	xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/
	http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">The image of the Public Library in Information Society</dc:title>
	<dc:title xml:lang="pt-BR">Imagem da biblioteca pública na Sociedade da Informação</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Bernardino, Maria Cleide Rodrigues; Universidade Federal do Ceará, UFC/Campus Cariri</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Suaiden, Emir Jose; Universidade de Brasília - UnB.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Ciência da Informação</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Public Library; Image of the Public Library; Public Library - Information Society</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="pt-BR">Ciência da Informação</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="pt-BR">Biblioteca Pública; Imagem da Biblioteca Pública; Biblioteca Pública – Sociedade da Informação.</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">The Public Library occupies a prominent place in the information society by bringing in its core processing, use and dissemination of information, which related to information technology and communication ensures the user needs to recover information. In turn, that this recovery are needed to become effective professionals qualified and knowledgeable resources and strategies permeated by information society and technological apparatus sufficient to support these activities. In this sense, the story draws a image of the public library that ranges from classical to unnecessary, depending on the time and context. However, it is inevitable reflection about the paradigm shift that surround the scaffold around the image of the public library, which in the information society should have his image in association with other aesthetic meanings themselves the context in which we live. To understand the term image, we will base on Villafañe (1998), which gives his concept of assimilation to the representation of a particular product, service or situation in people's minds. This idea is part of organizational culture and the library is constructed from the self-image of the organization, its image intentional and functional. This concept based on Gestalt theory (psychology) and institutional (management) will help draw the frame of reference to support for building the image of the public library.</dc:description>
	<dc:description xml:lang="pt-BR">A biblioteca pública ocupa lugar de destaque na sociedade da informação por trazer em sua essência o tratamento, uso e disseminação da informação, que associada às tecnologias da informação e da comunicação garante ao usuário a recuperação precisa da informação. Por sua vez, para que essa recuperação se efetive são necessários profissionais habilitados e conhecedores dos recursos e estratégias permeadas pela sociedade da informação; e aparato tecnológico suficiente que suporte estas atividades. Neste sentido, a história traça uma imagem da biblioteca pública que vai do erudito ao desnecessário, dependendo da época e contexto. Porém, é inevitável a reflexão acerca da mudança de paradigmas que circundam o arcabouço em torno da imagem da biblioteca pública, que na sociedade da informação deverá ter sua imagem associada a outros significados estéticos próprios do contexto em que estamos vivendo. Para entender o termo imagem, nos basearemos em Villafañe (1998), que atribui seu conceito à representação da assimilação de um determinado produto, serviço ou situação na mente das pessoas. Essa ideia faz parte da cultura organizacional da biblioteca e é construída a partir da autoimagem da organização, de sua imagem intencional e funcional. Essa concepção com base na teoria da Gestalt (psicologia) e institucional (administração) ajudarão a desenhar o quadro referencial de apoio para a construção da imagem da biblioteca pública.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="pt-BR">Universidade de São Paulo. Faculdade de Filosofia, Ciências e Letras de Ribeirão Preto</dc:publisher>
	<dc:contributor xml:lang="en-US"></dc:contributor>
	<dc:contributor xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:contributor>
	<dc:date>2011-06-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en-US"></dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>http://www.revistas.usp.br/incid/article/view/42338</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.11606/issn.2178-2075.v2i1p130-142</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="pt-BR">InCID: Revista de Ciência da Informação e Documentação; v. 2, n. 1 (2011); 130-142</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2178-2075</dc:source>
	<dc:language>por</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>http://www.revistas.usp.br/incid/article/view/42338/46009</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
	</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
