<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="https://agora.emnuvens.com.br/lib/pkp/xml/oai2.xsl" ?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/
		http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
	<responseDate>2015-10-29T19:23:49Z</responseDate>
	<request verb="GetRecord" metadataPrefix="oai_dc" identifier="oai:agora.periodicos.emnuvens.com.br:article/565">https://agora.emnuvens.com.br/ra/oai</request>
	<GetRecord>
		<record>
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:agora.periodicos.emnuvens.com.br:article/565</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-10-28T18:50:38Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>ra:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc
	xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/
	http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Applicability of the Access to Information Act in the public administration; a theoretical discussion about the challenges and prospects for modern archival</dc:title>
	<dc:title xml:lang="pt-BR">Aplicabilidade da Lei de Acesso à Informação na gestão pública: uma discussão teórica acerca dos desafios e perspectivas para a arquivística moderna</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Pereira, Deiverson</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Santa Anna, Jorge</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Archival; Library; Information Science</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Citizenship; information; Public administration; Access to information; archival</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Citizenship; information; Public administration; Access to information; archival</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="pt-BR">Arquivologia; Biblioteconomia; Ciência da Informação</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="pt-BR">Cidadania; Informação; Administração Pública; Acesso à informação; Arquivista;</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="pt-BR">Cidadania; Informação; Administração Pública; Acesso à informação; Arquivista</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">With the enactment of Law n. 12 527 of 18 November 2011, which regulates access to information referred to in paragraph XXXIII of Art. 5, clause II, § 3. Art. 37 and § 2 of art. 216 of the Federal Constitution, the Public Administration must make available to the average person any information that is not restricted by law. After the emergence of this law, known as the Access to Information Act (LAI), the demands of access to information have increased visibility by users, making them more demanding in their requests, consequently, charging the public service more complete service and According to the legislation, on the other hand, he had to improve the quality of their services, meeting the legal requirements, guaranteeing fundamental rights to citizens, so as to enable access and accessibility to public information with greater transparency and speed. Thus, it reflects about the applicability of this law within the public administration, demonstrating the challenges and prospects for the archivist. Through literature, discusses the relationship between information and citizenship; contextualizes the emergence and proposals of LAI; and presents the interference of the archivist in the applicability of the law. It concludes that the LAI has effective proposals, given disclose the State's actions, enabling the principles governing citizenship and democratic state. However, that this law achieves its objectives, there must be participation of the archivist in managing and informational provision, aimed at effective access and use by citizens.</dc:description>
	<dc:description xml:lang="pt-BR">Com o advento da Lei n. 12.527, de 18 de novembro de 2011, que regula o acesso a informações, previsto no inciso XXXIII do art. 5., no inciso II do § 3. do art. 37 e no § 2. do art. 216 da Constituição Federal, a Administração Pública deve disponibilizar ao cidadão comum toda e qualquer informação que não seja restrita por lei. Após o surgimento dessa lei, conhecida como Lei de Acesso à Informação (LAI), as demandas de acesso à informação tiveram maior visibilidade pelos usuários, tornando-os mais exigentes em suas solicitações, consequentemente, cobrando do serviço público um atendimento mais completo e de acordo com a legislação, que, por outro lado, teve que aprimorar a qualidade dos seus serviços, atendendo aos preceitos legais, garantindo direitos fundamentais aos cidadãos, de modo a viabilizar o acesso e acessibilidade às informações públicas com maior transparência e rapidez. Assim, reflete acerca da aplicabilidade dessa lei no âmbito da gestão pública, demonstrando os desafios e perspectivas para o arquivista. Através de pesquisa bibliográfica, discute a relação existente entre informação e cidadania; contextualiza o surgimento e propostas da LAI; e, apresenta a interferência do arquivista na aplicabilidade dessa lei. Conclui-se que a LAI apresenta propostas efetivas, haja vista transparecer as ações do Estado, viabilizando, os princípios que regem a cidadania e o Estado Democrático. No entanto, para que essa lei atinja seus objetivos, é preciso que haja participação do arquivista no gerenciamento e na disponibilização informacional, visando o efetivo acesso e uso por parte dos cidadãos. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="pt-BR">ÁGORA ISSN 0103-3557</dc:publisher>
	<dc:contributor xml:lang="en-US"></dc:contributor>
	<dc:contributor xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:contributor>
	<dc:date>2015-10-20</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="pt-BR">Pesquisa bibliográfica</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en-US">Bibliographic search</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://agora.emnuvens.com.br/ra/article/view/565</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="pt-BR">ÁGORA ISSN 0103-3557; v. 25, n. 51 (2015); 209-233</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0103-3557</dc:source>
	<dc:language>por</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://agora.emnuvens.com.br/ra/article/view/565/pdf</dc:relation>
	<dc:coverage xml:lang="en-US">Brazil</dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage xml:lang="en-US">Modernism</dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage xml:lang="en-US">Bibliographic search</dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage xml:lang="pt-BR">Brasil</dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage xml:lang="pt-BR">Modernismo</dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage xml:lang="pt-BR">Pesquisa bibliográfica</dc:coverage>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="pt-BR">Direitos autorais 2015 ÁGORA ISSN 0103-3557</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
	</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
