<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="https://agora.emnuvens.com.br/lib/pkp/xml/oai2.xsl" ?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/
		http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
	<responseDate>2015-10-29T19:22:46Z</responseDate>
	<request verb="GetRecord" metadataPrefix="oai_dc" identifier="oai:agora.periodicos.emnuvens.com.br:article/555">https://agora.emnuvens.com.br/ra/oai</request>
	<GetRecord>
		<record>
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:agora.periodicos.emnuvens.com.br:article/555</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-10-21T14:40:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>ra:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc
	xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/
	http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">The organic information as an interdisciplinary subject: the relationship between Arquvística and Information Science under the representation in archives</dc:title>
	<dc:title xml:lang="pt-BR">A informação orgânica enquanto um objeto interdisciplinar: as relações entre a Arquivística e a Ciência da Informação no âmbito da representação em arquivos</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Bragato Barros, Thiago Henrique</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Rodrigues Martins, Wanessa</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Archival</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Archival; Information Science; Files representation; Organic information</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Representation Archives</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="pt-BR">Arquivologia</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="pt-BR">Arquivística; Ciência da Informação; Representação em Arquivos; Informação Orgânica</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="pt-BR">Representação Arquivística</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">It is considered the Archives a discipline that has interdisciplinary characteristics, particularly related to the Information Science in the Brazilian context. In this sense, the aim is through this article work with the concept of organic information as an object of Archival and Information Science. The following builds a parallel between representation for Archival and Information Science. The science of Information offers epistemological and methodological support to the Archives, able to make it, in effect, a scientific discipline. The Archives, in turn, gives you technical tools for the documentary treatment and privileged universe of action. Therefore, we consider this research as theoretical and documentary that examines the literature of both areas in the Brazilian context. Methodologically, it uses the content analysis as a way to approach the subject. If the objective is through this literature review and this parallel constructed by means of comparative tables to understand the points of contact between the representation for Archival and Information Science. The aim is to contribute theoretically and methodologically for effective interdisciplinary construction of the Science of Information and Archives under the representation and documentary treatment.</dc:description>
	<dc:description xml:lang="pt-BR">Considera-se a Arquivística uma disciplina que possui características interdisciplinares, especialmente relacionada à Ciência da Informação na conjuntura brasileira. Neste sentido, visa-se por meio deste artigo trabalhar com o conceito de informação orgânica enquanto objeto da Arquivística bem como da Ciência da Informação.  A seguir constrói-se um paralelo entre a representação para a Arquivística e para a Ciência da Informação. A ciência da Informação oferece aporte epistemológico-metodológico à Arquivística, capazes de torná-la, efetivamente, uma disciplina científica. A Arquivística, por sua vez, lhe concede instrumentos técnicos para o tratamento documental e um universo privilegiado de atuação. Portanto, considera-se esta pesquisa como teórica e documental que analisa a literatura de ambas as áreas no contexto brasileiro. Metodologicamente, utiliza-se da análise de conteúdo como forma de abordagem ao tema.  Objetiva-se por meio desta revisão de literatura e deste paralelo construído por meio de quadros comparativos compreender os pontos de contato entre a representação para a Arquivística e Ciência da Informação. Visa-se contribuir teórico-metodologicamente para a construção interdisciplinar efetiva entre a Ciência da Informação e Arquivística no âmbito da representação e do tratamento documental.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="pt-BR">ÁGORA ISSN 0103-3557</dc:publisher>
	<dc:contributor xml:lang="en-US"></dc:contributor>
	<dc:contributor xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:contributor>
	<dc:date>2015-10-20</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en-US"></dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://agora.emnuvens.com.br/ra/article/view/555</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="pt-BR">ÁGORA ISSN 0103-3557; v. 25, n. 51 (2015); 132-149</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0103-3557</dc:source>
	<dc:language>por</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://agora.emnuvens.com.br/ra/article/view/555/pdf</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>https://agora.emnuvens.com.br/ra/article/downloadSuppFile/555/49</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>https://agora.emnuvens.com.br/ra/article/downloadSuppFile/555/50</dc:relation>
	<dc:coverage xml:lang="en-US"></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage xml:lang="en-US"></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage xml:lang="en-US"></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage xml:lang="pt-BR"></dc:coverage>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="pt-BR">Direitos autorais 2015 ÁGORA ISSN 0103-3557</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
	</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
